A Guide to the Lena Estella Long Collection, 1763-1827
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Lena Estella Long Collection, 1763-1827
The Library of Virginia
21571
43 leaves
Lena Estella Long
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Lent for copying by Lena Estella Long, Luray, Virginia, 24 April 1939.
Biographical Information
Lena Estella Long was born 10 December 1878 in Craig, Missouri, and married William Martin Long (1881-1948) 5 September 1900. The Longs lived in Page County, Virginia, where Mrs. Long was a member of the Daughters of the American Revolution. She died 19 December 1968.
Scope and Content
Collection, 1763-1827, of Lena Estella Long (1878-1968) of Page County, Virginia, consisting of agreements, bonds, deeds, land grants, powers of attorney, and wills from Frederick, Dunmore, and Shenandoah Counties, Virginia. Much of the land involved in the deeds and land grants is located in present-day Page County, Virginia. Agreements, bonds, and powers of attorney concern individuals from Shenandoah County. One will was recorded in Frederick County, the other in Shenandoah County.
Contents List
- Will, dated 8 September 1763 and recorded 1 November 1763, of Matthias Selzer of Frederick County, Virginia.
- Deed, dated 25 September 1772 and recorded 28 April 1773, for certain lands in Dunmore [Shenandoah] County, Virginia, from John Sulcer to Michael Reader, both of Dunmore County.
- Deed, dated 23 November 1773 and recorded March 1781, for 15 acres in Shenandoah County, Virginia, from Samuel and Mary Leather to Chisley Shelly, all of Shenandoah County.
- Deed, dated 5 October 1782 and recorded 28 November 1782, for 16 acres in Shenandoah County from Matthias and Eve Selcer to Jacob Strickler, all of Shenandoah County.
- Deed of lease, dated 20 August 1785 and recorded 25 August 1785, for 177 acres in Shenandoah County between Michael Reader and Philip Long, both of Shenandoah County.
- Deed of release, dated 20 August 1785 and recorded 25 August 1785, for 177 acres in Shenandoah County between Michael and Catherine Reader and Philip Long, all of Shenandoah County.
- Land grant, 23 July 1787, for 155 acres in Shenandoah County from Lieutenant Governor Beverley Randolph to Michael Reader.
- Deed, dated 25 October 1787 and recorded 26 October 1787, for 36 acres in Shenandoah County from Benjamin and Mary Strickler to John Strickler, all of Shenandoah County.
- Agreement, 15 August 1788, between Philip Long and George Bungaman of Shenandoah County.
- Land grant, 30 July 1782, for 177 acres in Shenandoah County from Governor Henry Lee to Jonathan Watson.
- Deed, dated 8 April 1794 and recorded 9 April 1794, for 155 acres in Shenandoah County from Michael and Catherine Reader to Philip Long.
- Deed, dated and recorded 14 October 1794, for 177 acres in Shenandoah County from Jonathan Watson by his attorney Joseph Strickler to Christian Shelley of Shenandoah County.
- Bond, 19 March 1798, from John Strickler to Philip Long.
- Deed, dated 10 April 1798 and recorded 8 October 1799, for four tracts of land in Shenandoah County from John and Barbara Strickler to Philip Long.
- Deed, dated 1 February 1809 and recorded 12 June 1809, for four tracts of land in Shenandoah County from Philip Long to Reuben Long of Shenandoah County.
- Deed, dated 5 June 1813, for 250 acres in Shenandoah County from Alexander Hay to Peter Hay, both of Shenandoah County.
- Deed, dated 5 June 1813, for 311 1/2 acres in Shenandoah County from Alexander Hay to David and John Hay of Shenandoah County.
- Power of attorney, August 1823, from George Hetich of Pennsylvania to Paschal Graves of Shenandoah County.
- Will, 1827, of Reuben Long of Shenandoah County.